http://www.nd.gov/tax/privacy-policy/

Skip to main content
Living2020 Main Street Summit SponsorsArts & CultureCost of LivingHealth Wellness and FamiliesLearning for a LifetimeMain Street NDAbout Main Street Summit2020 Main Street Summit SpeakersMain Street SponsorsOutdoor RecreationSafetySports and Leisure ActivitiesWeatherND RoadsWorkingFinding a Job and Building a CareerMoving to North DakotaTools & ResourcesIndustriesAdvanced ManufacturingAutonomous SystemsEnergy & Natural ResourcesFood & AgricultureInformation TechnologyTourismBusiness21st Century WorkforceBusiness Tools & ResourcesIncentives & FundingStarting or Expanding BusinessTrade & ExportsTransportation & LogisticsNews & EventsCensus 2020NewsEventsPublic MeetingsMedia GalleryGovernmentWelcome from Governor BurgumCitizen ServicesState AgenciesLocal GovernmentState GovernmentFederal GovernmentTribal GovernmentsMilitary and Veterans AffairsND Transparency
Living
Arts & Culture
Cost of Living
Health Wellness and Families
Learning for a Lifetime
Main Street ND
Outdoor Recreation
Safety
General Information
Records received by the State of North Dakota from web sites are subject to the same controls and uses as records collected by governmental offices visited in person and are open to the public upon request unless otherwise specifically provided by law. You should check with the specific agency you are providing information to, to determine whether the information you provide them will be held in confidence or must be released upon request by a member of the public.
Domain Information
Google Analytics is used to help analyze how users use the site. This analytical tool uses cookie's, which are text files placed on your computer, to collect standard internet log information and visitor behavior information in an anonymous form. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) is transmitted to Google. This information is then used to evaluate visitor's use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity.
We will not (and will not allow any third party) to use the statistical analytics tool to track or to collect any personally identifiable information of visitors to our site. We will not associate any data gathered from this site with any personally identifying information from any source as part of our use of the Google statistical analytics tool.
Hotjar, a website analytics and feedback tool, is also used in order to better understand users’ needs and to optimize this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices (in particular device's IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy by clicking on this link.
You can opt-out to the creation of a user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this opt-out link.
Visual Web Optimizer (VWO), a website testing and optimization tool, is used to evaluate the effectiveness of some websites/applications. For example, VWO can be used to determine if the web page title "Agency by Alphabet" is more or less intuitive than the title "List of State Agencies."
For more information, visit the VWO Data Privacy Resources.
Opt-out of VWO tracking by following this opt-out link.
Personal Information
To protect the information being gathered this site has security measures in place including firewalls, encryption, and authenticated access to internal databases where needed.
Specific information regarding encryption, credit card information, social security numbers and cookies will be addressed on the pages that use this information.
If you send an email from nd.gov, the email address will be collected as a means to reply to you. We may forward your message to another agency for appropriate action.
Retention of Information
The information collected on this site is retained in accordance with the Record Retention Schedules developed by this office.
Contact Information
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please contact us.
